[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 19]
Xia Yingying left me two things.
The first is this hairpin.
The other is Qingrong.
After Xia Yingying passed away,
I was soft-hearted
and brought her back.
I raised her day and night.
We developed a bond,
and also an obsession.
In my heart,
Qingrong and Qingru
are both my own flesh and blood.
There is no difference.
You are so kind, Madam.
Maybe this is retribution.
I just hope Qingrong
will never know the truth.
[Harmony Among Kin]
You're here.
Third Sister, you're burning the Rebirth Sutra
for Fifth Madam again.
Fortunately, the truth has come to light,
allowing the two of us
to peacefully coexist.
Previously, I saw you as the daughter of my enemy,
but I didn't expect to have hated the wrong person.
If it weren't for you,
the real culprit who killed my mother and brother
would probably still be gloating today.
But I...
Like you,
I lost my mother at a young age.
Therefore, in this residence,
the person who understands you best
should be me.
As your mother's child,
if you live under the same roof as your enemy
and remain indifferent,
that'd make you truly unfilial
and heartless.
Third Sister,
I don't blame you,
and you shouldn't mind either.
I don't mind at all.
Yes,
I did hate you before
and always made things difficult for you.
But you didn't suffer either.
Anyway, every time I teased you,
I was the one who ended up unlucky.
Qingyuan,
I'm sorry.
And thank you, really.
Mei Yinghua
received a heavy punishment from Father.
If Fifth Madam knew this in the afterlife,
she could rest in peace.
But there's one thing I don't understand.
[Harmony Among Kin]
Concubine Mei is not proficient in pharmacology,
so how could she come up with such a subtle poison scheme?
Or is it really as she said,
she only wanted Fifth Madam to miscarry
and had no intention to kill?
That cruel woman bullied my mother
and managed internal affairs for years.
Naturally, she had no good intentions.
Since childhood,
you grew up under Mother's roof
with Second Sister.
You always disregarded others.
As such, you might have
overlooked certain things.
You've just recently discovered that
the real murderer is not my mother,
but Mei Yinghua.
The Xie family
hides far too many secrets.
What you hear
and see
is not necessarily the truth.
Even though Mei Yinghua is vicious,
she knew
she couldn't escape her crimes.
So why did she bite back for no reason?
Why isn't anyone accusing her?
A-Are you out of your mind?
You told me about the euphorbia!
Though I no longer hate you,
I don't need to hear you say these things.
I've been in the residence for a long time.
If there's really anything,
I'd know.
Lord Xie.
Having just lost your beloved son,
you still insist on stepping up to take charge.
I admire you.
I will substitute tea for wine
to toast you, Lord Xie.
-To Lord Xie. -To Lord Xie.
My trivial family matters
have troubled you, my lords.
Thank you.
Please.
Please, my lord.
Yan Rui has left.
It is settled that Wei Changyan
colluded with
the northern bandits.
I would like to hear
what your next steps
will be.
Yan Rui is finally cleared out of Hengtang.
Wei Changyan left behind a huge mess of unresolved accounts.
We still need you to make decisions, Lord Xie.
Not so.
Hengtang belongs to all of you,
not just me.
In all matters,
we must join forces
and deliberate together.
-Yes. -Yes.
In my opinion,
we should follow the old rules.
The more you work, the more you gain.
What do you think?
Good.
Your Lordship is right.
Lord Xie,
with you in charge,
we naturally have no objections.
Right, my lords?
That's right.
No objections at all.
Lord Xie,
Wei Changyan left a sum of money at the dock.
Counting it
will take some effort.
I am willing to share your burden, Lord Xie.
Lord Xie, I'm also free lately.
I'm willing to help settle Wei Changyan's old accounts too
and share your burden, Lord Xie.
I'm free too.
We are also willing to share your burden, Lord Xie.
Whose people are they?
This...
Death is at your door,
yet you are still fighting over a few pieces of silver.
This is...
Lord Xie,
[Yongjia County Lady, Pei Yuting]
you really know how to lead your subordinates.
How dare you?
Who are you?
My lords are discussing important matters here.
How can a woman like you come here?
Guards!
Wait!
If I'm not mistaken,
could you be
the adopted daughter of the Imperial Noble Consort,
sister of Pei Liangyong,
Yongjia County Lady?
County Lady?
Greetings, My Lady.
I, Pei Yuting, haven't been in Hengtang for a long time,
but you still remember me.
It seems
you are not completely foolish.
We wouldn't dare.
Founding Countess
was involved in disaster relief efforts
and met with an accident.
I was deeply saddened.
Are you here regarding that matter?
I missed seeing off my brother and sister-in-law.
But,
I'm just in time to see you all off.
See us off?
No...
What do you mean?
I heard that with Lord Xie in Hengtang,
our Pei family will always be at a disadvantage.
If today,
Lord Xie is willing to beg me
and make me happy,
I might be willing to tell you something.
Please enlighten me.
The fake Yan Rui you let slip
is actually a favored minister of His Majesty,
Shen Run.
Even the Prince has to treat him with respect.
Do you know what's even more terrifying?
His father was Shen Zhibai.
This...
Now he has requested an edict to return to Hengtang.
Tell me,
if he met the lot of you
who framed his father,
now that he is back,
how would he deal with you?
This... I...
Especially you, the Xie family.
Falling into his hands
is only a matter of time.
This...
How can I ensure my family's survival?
We're doomed.
A fake Yan Rui left,
and a real king of hell is coming.
What do we do now?
That's right.
Lord Xie.
You have to think of a way quickly.
-Lord Xie. -Lord Xie.
-Do something. -Protect my family, Lord Xie.
Yes, Lord Xie, please say something.
Lord Xie,
are you really not afraid at all?
Lord Shen Zhibai
was a close friend of mine when he was alive.
Since he is the son of an old friend,
I can't wait to catch up with him.
What is there to fear?
It seems
Lord Xie has already found a way out.
What about the rest of you?
I'm afraid it won't be so easy for you.
My Lady.
My wife also has water transport gangs at the docks.
If you want them,
I will offer them all.
Please save my life.
My family has a dock.
-I'll surrender it to the Pei family. -Please protect us, My Lady.
-My Lady. -Shoo, shoo!
We have granaries and rice barns!
They are all for the Pei family.
Alright.
My Lady.
Let go.
I don't have the final say.
You need Lord Xie's approval.
Lord Xie, please say something.
The Pei family
manages hundreds of water transport gangs.
Back then, one of Lord Shen Zhibai's
major crimes
was embezzling profits from water transport.
Now that Shen Run is investigating things,
My Lady, although it has nothing to do with you,
I'm afraid
the Pei family cannot escape involvement.
If I'm not wrong,
the Pei family is already caught in Shen Run's schemes.
I suggest
the Pei family figure out a way to protect yourselves soon.
I just said it.
Hengtang belongs to everyone,
not just me.
We can discuss everything together.
Besides,
the County Lady has returned.
She is wise, too.
I suggest letting
the County Lady take charge of the overall situation.
You can all discuss together
and do what you want best.
I will listen to you all.
Don't say that, Lord Xie.
Lord Xie, what should we do?
What year is this old tea from? It's so bitter.
Lord Xie,
it's time for something new.
Okay.
[Distinguished Family]
What?
Call off the engagement?
Yes.
Reporting to the Master
and Head Madam,
the Pei family says
the Eldest Lady
is cursed to harm her mother and husband,
so they sent a notice to call off the engagement.
Pei Liangyong
is utterly ridiculous.
How can marriage
be treated as child's play?
The three letters and six etiquettes have all been completed.
He can't just call it off whenever he wants.
Calm down, Master.
They just got engaged,
and Madam Pei died a tragic death.
Presumably, the Founding Count
has other thoughts.
Maybe he thinks it's bad luck.
What did you say?
So unruly.
The heir of the Founding Count is in mourning.
They certainly won't be able to marry
within the next 3 years.
But Qinghe can't wait that long.
Why don't we find her another family?
Father.
Lanshan and I have an agreement.
As soon as his mourning period is over, we will get married.
I don't want to marry anyone else.
Qinghe.
You are not yet married.
Although you have an engagement,
meeting privately
will give people cause for gossip.
Exactly.
If this gets out one day,
people will say the women of the Xie family are unchaste,
and that's why the engagement was broken.
It'd really disgrace our family name.
Mother.
This is just an excuse the Pei family made up
to break the engagement.
Instead of seeking justice,
why are we blaming Eldest Sister?
Father.
I think the Pei family
isn't targeting Eldest Sister,
but trying to embarrass our Xie family.
Qinghe.
You really have an unfortunate fate.
She should be punished if she deserves it.
Don't let our inner court affairs
ruin the friendship between the two families.
Okay.
Stop talking.
Everyone, stop talking.
I am busy with official duties every day,
and I still have to listen to your chattering when I get back.
A minister's virtue is loyalty.
A son's virtue is filial piety.
And a woman's virtue
is her wifely duties.
I think you have all forgotten them in this residence.
Each of you has your own ideas.
Wenzhuo,
don't let me worry about
the matters of the inner household.
You make the decisions.
If anyone dares to disobey,
punish them with family rules without mercy.
Yes.
Eldest Lady Qinghe
has misbehaved
and damaged the reputation of the Xie family.
She is grounded for 3 months
and must copy the Admonitions for Women
a hundred times.
Qingyuan,
if you feel sorry for your eldest sister,
kneel in the ancestral hall with her tonight.
To think you wanted Father to speak for you.
You should realize clearly
who is in charge of the Xie's inner household
from now on.
Eldest Sister.
Fourth Sister.
I'm sorry.
I dragged you into this again.
Don't blame yourself.
Mother
is angry that I asked Third Madam about the past,
so she deliberately targeted you.
It's me who dragged you into this.
What happened between you and Young Master Pei?
The day before yesterday,
didn't he come to the herbal shop to look for you?
I have no idea.
[Respectful exchange of birth details] [A match made in heaven]
He clearly said
he would marry me in 3 years.
But it's only been 3 days,
and the narrative has changed.
Something must be wrong.
Don't worry.
Something might have happened in the Pei family.
I will go to the Pei residence tomorrow
and get an explanation for you.
Madam.
The Pei family sent someone to deliver generous gifts today.
They said Fourth Lady
went to the Pei family for an explanation,
and they came to apologize to Eldest Lady.
It's Qingyuan causing trouble again.
It doesn't matter.
Anyway, this marriage with the Founding Count's residence is ruined.
Just keep Qinghe
locked up for now.
Let the third branch know
the rules of the Xie household.
Nothing else matters.
The most important thing
is Zhenglun's funeral.
Have you done
everything needed?
Rest assured, Madam.
The belongings of Eldest Young Master just arrived,
and I've already checked them.
That item is not there.
That's good.
My Lady.
Madam Hu is really too vicious.
Even though the Pei family has apologized,
she still won't let Eldest Lady out.
In this residence,
the deaths of Concubine Xia and my mother,
and Concubine Mei going mad,
were all her doing.
Tomorrow
is Eldest Brother's funeral.
It's time for the guilty
to be buried with him.
Lord Xie,
my condolences.
-Xie. -Lord Xie, my condolences.
My condolences.
Xie, my condolences.
Zhenglun died for his nation.
The men of Hengtang
will never forget this.
My brother died for his nation.
But at his funeral,
even his body couldn't be sent home.
The Northern Frontier is far,
and the war is raging.
They could only gather his clothes
and send them back by fast horse.
Had I known it was a final farewell,
I would have spoken to him
much more in the past.
Chunzhi insisted on coming,
but he is really unwell.
I didn't want him to bring any illness
to disturb Zhenglun's spirit.
Thank you for your thoughtfulness, Madam Li.
It is comforting enough that the two of you could come.
Ever since you arrived,
the Xie family has had no peace.
Watch your words, Second Sister.
We're at Eldest Brother's funeral.
How can you say such baseless things?
How is it baseless?
Qingru,
stop making a scene.
Yongjia County Lady has arrived!
My Lady.
Apologies for not welcoming you.
Greetings, My Lady.
Lord Xie.
It's getting late.
You should begin.
Master,
shall we begin?
My Xie family
is a family that upholds loyalty, valor,
filial piety, and righteousness.
My eldest son, Zhenglun,
dedicated himself to the nation,
protecting our land and our people.
In his final moments,
he fought bravely against the enemy,
dyeing his battle robes with blood.
He has brought
honor to the ancestors of the Xie family.
Today,
I lead the entire Xie family
to respectfully welcome the general's armor
back home.
The general's armor is returning for burial!
There seems to be
a letter within the armor.
[Respectfully to Brother Zhenglun, from younger brother Zhengjun]
Did this belong to Eldest Brother?
Since it was his belonging,
let's burn it together for Zhenglun.
Nanny Liu.
Yes.
No!
Out of my way!
I want to know what my brother said before he died.
This letter
appearing here suddenly
must mean that Eldest Brother
still has some unfulfilled wishes.
Thank you both.
It's our duty to avenge the heroic
and redress any grievances.
Go.
Expose that evil woman's true colors
in front of all of Hengtang.
We will support you from here.
There is one more thing
I need your help with.
Tell us.
At my eldest brother's funeral tomorrow,
this letter
must appear among his belongings.
Leave it to us.
[Respectfully to Brother Zhenglun, from younger brother Zhengjun]
Zhengjun.
The sudden appearance of this letter
is highly suspicious.
Today is your eldest brother's funeral.
We must not lose our manners.
Come down first.
To my dear brother Zhenglun.
Mother has been ill at the estate for a long time.
The doctor said
her condition is incurable.
Zhengjun!
This is the mourning hall.
We cannot afford any complications.
Listen to me.
Come down.
Father.
Master.
This is a family letter,
not his last words.
It is not suitable to be read here.
My wife is right.
This is a family letter.
Don't read it in public.
Come down.
Mother probably doesn't have much time left.
Zhengjun!
She resents you in the end
for abandoning her while she's seriously ill
to go to the battlefield.
You sacrificed your family for the greater good.
You failed to repay her,
which makes you unfilial.
As Mother lay on her deathbed,
I hope for your swift victory and return.
If she cannot see you one last time,
I fear she will not rest in peace
and will die with resentment.
This is...
A huge taboo on the battlefield.
That's right.
The slightest negligence can cost a life.
That's why letters to the border
have always reported only good news.
Who would write such a letter to the frontline?
Exactly.
In that case,
Zhenglun must have died in battle
because he was eager to finish things
and rush back to see his mother one last time.
Makes sense.
That makes sense.
Zhengjun.
Who wrote this letter?
Respectfully yours,
younger brother Zhengjun.
It wasn't me.
It wasn't me!
I clearly...
I clearly wrote,
"Mother is in good health,
and I am studying diligently
without slacking off."
How did this happen?
Fourth Sister,
we wrote this letter together.
How did this happen?
I'm afraid
the letter was swapped.
You're right.
Someone must have swapped the letter.
Someone must have!
Father.
Grandmother.
My brother was murdered.
He was killed by this letter!
Shu.
Here.
Let's finish the funeral first.
As for this matter,
we will discuss it when we go back.
Yes.
Come down.
No!
I must clarify it here.
Second Brother,
who did you give the letter to that day?
Tell me.
Where did you take the letter after I passed it to you?
I...
Speak!
Yes.
The Second Young Master indeed gave it to me.
Yes,
I was the one who sent Nanny Liu
to take the letter.
I wanted to help
send it out quickly.
But after Nanny Liu
got the letter,
the rain
had completely soaked it.
Not a single word could be read.
I guessed
Zhengjun must have wanted to report the family affairs
to Zhenglun,
so I had someone draft one.
I meant well.
You...
You meant well?
If you meant well, you should have said it clearly to my face!
I really...
I didn't expect the Head Madam of the Xie family
to do something like this.
It's no different from murdering a concubine's son.
Keep your voice down.
Don't talk nonsense!
What Mother said is also true.
At that time, Mei Yinghua was about to die.
Mother
definitely didn't do it on purpose.
Father,
there must be something wrong with this matter.
Don't be provoked by false accusations.
Father,
my brother hasn't been buried yet.
This matter can't just end like this.
Father,
Zhenglun
was not only the eldest son of the Xie family
and our respected eldest brother,
but also a loyal martyr
known to everyone in Hengtang.
This is not as simple as a family affair.
The people who came today
are all distinguished guests.
If we don't give them an explanation,
how can we demonstrate the righteousness of our Xie family?
How will we convince the public?
Father.
Eldest Lady is right.
A loyal and heroic soul has died,
yet the cause of death is suspicious.
If it's not thoroughly investigated,
how can we possibly sit idly by?
Indeed!
Mother,
you have known me for decades.
You know very well
how I treat the Xie family.
I am a daughter
of the prominent Hu family.
You also know
what my character is like.
Old Madam, please discern the truth
and uphold justice for me.
Mother...
Exactly. How can it not be investigated?
The evidence is here.
How can we not investigate?
Enough!
Everyone.
Today's funeral
is to mourn Zhenglun,
who sacrificed his life for the nation.
May his heroic soul live forever.
If there are hidden circumstances...
after the Xie family investigates it,
we will definitely give everyone
an explanation.
Everyone.
The general's armor
will be placed in the ancestral hall.
When his remains
are brought back in the future,
they will be buried together.
Today's matter is concluded.
Please return to your residences.
This...
Yes.
Lord Shen, Commander of the Palace Guard, has arrived.
Yan Rui?
It's Yan Rui.
Didn't they say it was Lord Shen?
Yan Rui?
How dare he come to the Xie family?
And he chose to come during the funeral.
Commander of the Palace Guard,
Shen Run,
here to comfort the heroic spirit.
I apologize for
disturbing your peace.
My dear friend,
have a safe journey.
The imperial edict is here.
I heard that a family of martyrs
will inherit the righteous spirit of heaven and earth.
[Commander of the Palace Guard, Shen Run]
As such, Zhenglun of the Xie family
was endowed with a resolute posture
and the courage of a defender.
Armed and armored,
he sacrificed himself in battle.
He is hereby posthumously awarded
the title of Commandant of Loyalty and Power.
He shall be enshrined in the Martyrs' Shrine of the prefecture,
and bestowed rites in spring and autumn.
His family shall be granted a hundred taels of gold
and fifty bolts of silk
to compensate the kins left behind.
His father, Xie Shu,
has taught his son well
for instilling loyalty and integrity.
He shall be granted the title of Earl of Zhongyong
and promoted to Grand Officer of the Secondary First Rank
to commend his family's teachings.
A plaque honoring the loyal Xie family shall be built to perpetuate
their renown for posterity.
Lord Xie,
please receive the edict.
I humbly
receive the edict.
I, Xie Shu,
thank His Majesty for the profound grace.
My dear nephew,
I didn't expect
you to be the son of an old friend.
Your father,
Lord Shen Zhibai,
was my best friend.
Do not be in a hurry to exchange pleasantries with me, Your Lordship.
I have a second edict to read.
Shen Che.
In the 39th year of the Jingyu era,
Shen Zhibai took office in Hengtang,
and broke the monopoly of the prominent families.
He found out that they colluded with the authorities
under the guise of the Green Sprouts Law,
forcing the civilians
into high-interest loans
and turning the imperial court's benevolent policy
into a vicious law.
From then on,
Shen Zhibai cracked down on the collusion between officials and merchants.
For a while, the politics were clean,
and the people lived in peace.
However,
in less than a year,
the prominent families colluded with the officials,
instigated the merchant guilds,
and united
to fabricate serious charges of corruption
against Shen Zhibai,
framing him collectively.
Overnight,
Shen Zhibai
went from a peerlessly honest and loyal official
to a world-shocking
corrupt official in Hengtang.
Back then, the Shen family was executed,
and only two children
narrowly escaped death.
From then on,
they became lonely wandering ghosts in this world.
I am
Shen Run,
son of Shen Zhibai.
By the Emperor's edict,
I am here to clear Shen Zhibai's name
and purge the heinous criminals from back then.
From today on,
regardless of their official rank,
anyone with evidence against them
will be handed over
to the Palace Guards to be punished according to the law.
Those who disobey orders
or cause trouble
will be executed immediately.
I don't accept this!
What does a case from years ago
have to do with me?
Open your damn eyes.
I am the eldest son of the Lin family in Hengtang!
Do you know
who my father...
Lin Bingcheng.
In the 5th year of Jingxi,
he forcibly seized a civilian woman and caused her death.
In the 7th year of Jingxi,
he allowed his servants to commit violence,
forcing dozens of farmers to sell their fertile land.
The evidence is conclusive.
Execute immediately.
Shen Run!
You set up a private court
and killed the innocent!
I will go to the Emperor
and report you!
I almost forgot.
You also allowed
your servants to commit violence.
And you,
Fang Ruike.
Not me.
Really, not me!
Not me!
Lord Xie, save me!